Mark L. Lintern

Computer Engineer

Motivated computer engineer with 10+ years of experience and proven full stack skills from **HTML** to **DevOps**. Seeking position with <Nretnil, Inc> that will allow me to push my abilities to the next level. I have developed many web applications in **Ruby** which enhanced and enabled faster testing processes. I am excited to accelerate a new team with the latest technologies and methods.

SKILLS



WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Quality Assurance Engineer

Oracle Corporation

February 2017 - March 2019 Indianapolis, IN, USA

- Continuation of Quality Assurance Engineering role with additional responsibilites.
- Engineered and Implemented code changes to assist with development team for bugs and design updates.
- Maintained Saltstack configuration scripts for development, test, qa, and production environments. As well as scripts for bootstrapping developers host machines.
- Served as Compendium's project manager. Tracked and reported on development progress to assure deadlines were not missed.
- Lead Quality Assurance Engineer for a new Application Management Cloud Product (AMS) within the Oracle Cloud.
- Created and maintained an automation testing suite for the Oracle Marketing Cloud Framework application written in Java on top of the Selendium Webdriver framework
- Performed deployments of docker containers to our OMC Framework QA environtment through a Kubernetes management software, Rancher

O Quality Assurance Engineer

Oracle Corporation

January 2014 - February 2017 Indianapolis, IN, USA

- Reviewed and tested new features and bug fix merge requests using a locally maintained development environment as well as our public facing test environment
- Developed and maintained **Ruby** web application with functionalities that include network cloning, network population, and content scramble for the Compendium product.
- Created and maintained an automation testing suite for the Compendium application written in **Ruby** on top of the **Selendium Webdriver** framework.
- Facilitated migration of DNS, email, and website during the Compendium acquisition by Oracle.

Implementation Specialist

Compendium

July 2012 - January 2014 Indianapolis, IN, USA

- Implementated customer designs from Photoshop into HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and JQuery in our template management tool.
- Wrote and execute content import and export scripts in **PHP** and **Ruby** using the Compendium Rest API.
- Planned and Executed the office move, which included designing and setup of wiring tower.
- Split Time between company Integrations, Implementation and Maintenance of Web Designs, and Product Support.
- Migrated support request system from Salesforce to a Zendesk Salesforce integration.
- Completed support requests via phone and email and tracked them with Zendesk.
- Maintain internal systems, new user setups, user laptop configuration and companywide network configuration.

$\, igcap \,$ Information Technologies Administrator

Compendium

September 2010 - July 2012 Indianapolis, IN, USA

- Configured and maintained internal Active Directory, DHCP, and DNS Services.
- Created a move plan for office equipment, phone system and network organization.
- Executed email migration from Microsoft Exchange Server to Google Apps.
- Maintained Bacula backup system then migrated it to Windows Backup once everyone switched to MAC.
- Built and maintained internal web server build on Cent OS and Apache 2.
- Migrated DNS and DHCP from Linux BIND and DHCP to Windows Server 2008 Native Applications.
- Upgraded and Maintained Samba Network Storage Server with OpenLDAP and Active Directory integration.
- Migrated Network Storage from Samba Server to Windows Server.

Support Desk Analyst II

Qbase Inc.

November 2009 - September 2010 Beavercreek, OH, USA

- Performed routine outbound maintenance and repairs for hardware and software when necessary.
- Implemented and maintained security protocols company wide through group policy and third party software.
- Supported Altigen IP phone systems for managed companies as well as own internal phone network.
- o Created and maintained backup solutions, both on-line as well as physical drives, onsite and remotely.
- Trained new employees how to deal with common issues and software tools used within the company.
- Worked directly with the director of IT solutions.

Support Desk Analyst I

Qbase Inc.

May 2008 - November 2009

Beavercreek, OH, USA

- Performed remote, phone and email support using verbal instruction and remote control software.
- Supported the various software, hardware and network issues of more than 300 companies.
- Managed servers, workstations, routers and switches for approximately 30 companies subscribing to the managed services opportunities provided by the support staff with a third party software.
- Performed virus control measures for both pre infection prevention as well as post infection removal.
- Utilized the connectwise support application to track user requests from trouble ticket generation to resolution.
- · Hand built servers and workstations as well as installed hardware and software as requested by client.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

O Ruby Gems

- o compendium-api: utilizes compendium api with easy function calls for **Ruby** scripting. http://www.github.com/mlintern/compendium-api
- o nretnil-password: easy password, passphrase and uuid generation. https://github.com/nretnilkram/nretnil-password
- nretnil-fake-data: great for creating fake data such as names and dates. https://github.com/nretnilkram/nretnil-fake-data
- o nretnil-utilites: a set of utilies which extends Array, Hash, String and Integer classes. https://github.com/nretnilkram/nretnil-utilities
- nretnil-translate: a gem which translates text into Pig Latin or a simple scramble. https://github.com/nretnilkram/nretnil-translate

O Personal Websites for pleasure and assistance in development

- nretnil.com, practical site of my commonly used online tools built primarily with JavaScript and PHP.
- marklintern.com, personal site.
- o app.nretnil.com, **Ruby** Padrino App that handles account management, sessions, and authentication. Features include a curl generator and todo list.
- lintern.us, fun site with family photos displayed as if they are polarids on a cork board.
- sandybox.nretnil.com, **HTML** and **JavaScript** sandbox environment utilizing the JavaScript Ace Editor.
- dice.nretnil.com, randomized results for numbers, letters, 6-sided dice values, or custom characters.

O JavaScript / CSS Projects

• Fontstrap: CSS/JavaScript project combining Bootstrap and Fontawesome along with custom features and scripts. https://nretnilkram.github.io/fontstrap

EDUCATION

Wittenberg University

August 2004 - May 2008 Springfield, OH, USA

- Bachelor of Science Computer Science
- Bachelor of Arts Mathematics